Martin Haensch, B.Eng.

Menlo Park, CA ✓ Eligibility: Eligible to work in the U.S. Personal website: https://mhansch.com/

haenschmartin@gmail.com 🖂



https://www.linkedin.com/in/martin-haensch/



I am a motivated, reliable and dedicated German automation engineer and a full stack software developer with 4+ years of professional experience. I successfully launched my first self-developed industrial smart home web application "smart.ModoCorrente" on the German market in 2019. Since I recently moved to the US I am now looking for new professional challenges and development opportunities as a Software Engineer in the Bay Area.

EDUCATION

THM, Germany 10/2014 - 05/2018 **University of Applied Sciences Mittelhessen**

- **Degree**: B. Eng. (Electrical and Information Technology / Automation Engineer)
- Programming Coursework: Algorithms and data structures, Web Development, Databases, Front-End Engineer, RESTful WebAPIs, Design Patterns

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Entrepreneur & Software Engineer In cooperation with TeDatCo, Germany 05/2018 - 08/2020

smart.ModoCorrente (http://cloudswitching.de): Cloud-based PLC controlling system / smart home for industrial purposes

- Developing and programming of a functional PLC (S7-1200) that connects to an external server with minimal data
- Managing and documenting the entire project including training external staff
- Designing and programming of external interfaces to manage the connections of the external PLCs and to receive
- Administering and organizing No-SQL database relationships between multiple clients
- Programming a customer-friendly website to control PLC outputs and display current data
- Product information: Product launched in the German market in 2019, it optimizes maintenance while reducing downtime up to 100%. Reported savings from current customers up to 600k Euro.

Utilized: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, PHP, C#, MongoDB, TIA Portal, SCL, TCP/IP, Git

Electrical Engineer

TeDatCo GmbH, Germany

05/2018 - 08/2020

ModoCorrente (www.modoCorrente.de): System for remote control for renewable energy (wind, solar)

- Planning and installing control systems for renewable energy components (e.g., wind turbines)
- Creating networks for communication of diverse components (Ethernet, fieldbus)
- Splicing of glass fibres $(9\mu m 62,5\mu m)$ inclusive attenuating measurements of glass fibres
- Preparing technical drawings and Handling circuit diagrams
- Mounting control cabinet including on-site troubleshooting
- PLC Programming (Siemens S7-Series)

Utilized: TIA Portal, SPlan, Network technologies, Antenna technology, GSM, Bus Protocols, Glass fiber technologies

External Data Analyst

Philipps University Marburg, Germany

- Preparing and processing physiological data, e.g. with excel
- Scripting and facilitating data management for research staff

Utilized: MS Excel, VBA

Student Trainee

TeDatCo GmbH, Germany

10/2015 - 05/2018

01/2017 - 01/2018

Energy Timetable: VBA programmed automatic timetable.

- Programming of a VBA-Excel application for a large industrial food retailer (www.gemuese-meyer.de)
- General information: The application automatically creates an energy timetable

Utilized: MS Excel, VBA

Vocational Training / Office Manager

PMCS GmbH & Co. KG, Germany

08/2009 - 06/2012

Military Service (First-Aid Department)

German Military, Germany

07/2007 - 05/2009

PRIVATE PROJECTS

"Bartists" (in progress): Platform to connect bars and artists

Full stack web development project including frontend, backend and the design Utilized: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, PHP, Laravel, MySQL

"Plantguard" (smart home application): Controller to water plants automatically

Programming a NodeESP-Board with sensors and actors to water plants automatically Utilized: Arduino Software, C

SKILLS